#### Barskov Nikita

Data Engineer at Maxifier. Master Degree Student at Samara University.

¶ Samara, Russia

**\** +7(927)657-16-10

**Q** github.com/nikitabarskov

in linkedin.com/in/nikitabarskov

◀ t.me/nikitabarskov

# **Professional Summary**

I am a data engineer, an enthusiast for developing intelligent and modern applications that improve the quality of using and presenting data. I've got 2 years experience with implementing ETL with frameworks such as Apache Spark, Apache Hadoop, Apache Mesos. I'm well known in Python data analysis libraries, mathematical packages, and visualization tools.

I'm a bachelor of applied mathematics and physics with close to excellent average score (4.75/5.0). All mathematical and software engineer exercises have done with excellent score. My academic mathematical background allows me to take advantages of statistic, calculus and algebra methods for transforming data as I need and extracting necessary information for my work and needs.

Now, I'm a student at Samara University with an excellent (5.0/5.0 at the moment) average score. Masters programme "Data Mining and Quality Assurance" contains courses about software lifecycle, testing, basic business analysis knowledge and fundamentals of machine learning. My Master's thesis theme is «Forecasting users interacting with advertising content on sites» and it absolutely relates with my current job specific.

# Experience

Maxifier, Samara, Russia

**Intern** April 2017 – June 2017

Working on batch processing project in Maxifier as Intern.

Stack: Java, Guice, PostgreSQL, Spark, Hadoop, Aurora, Bazel, GitLab CI.

Data Engineer

June 2017 – Present

Developing the application for forecasting users interactions with advertising content and its evaluation.

Stack: Python/Scala, Spark, Hadoop, Mesos, Docker, MySQL, Akka, Slick, SciPy, Maven, GitHub.

### Education

Bachelor of Science

Samara University, Samara Russia

Master Degree Student
Data Analysis and Quality Assurance, Average Point 5.0

Applied Mathematics and Physics, Average Point 4.75

Sep 2013 – June 2017

September 2017 – Present

## Skills

Personal: rational, responsible, sociable

Base Skills: advanced knowledge in mathematics and application of these methods to ETL

Natural Languages: Russian (native), English (intermediate)

**Programming Languages:** Python 3 (intermediate knowledge for writing batch processing jobs and data science), Scala, Java (regular knowledge for writing services and batch processing jobs)

Frameworks and libraries: Apache Spark, Apache Hadoop, Apache Mesos, Docker, Scipy(Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib), Scikit-learn, Akka, Slick

Build Tools and VCS: Maven, Bazel, Git, Gitlab CI, Github

Others: fundamental knowledge about the development process (Process Cycle of Software Applications Development, methodologies, QA(methods and approaches), Bussiness and System Analytics(methods and approaches))